Stereographic Cards
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Stereographic Cards, 2.1.8
  - Verso: A Winter Morning in the Lovely Valley of Grindelwald, Switzerland: More glorious mountain scenery than that which encircles the spot, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 72-verso (Box 1607)
  - Entrance to the Wonderful Gorge of the Aar River, One of the Largest and Deepest in Switzerland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 73 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Entrance to the Aar River Gorge, Switzerland: We are in central Switzerland near Meiringen and some 18 miles east of Interlaken., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 73-verso (Box 1607)
  - The Wood Carver, Meringen, Switzerland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 74 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: A Wood Carver, Switzerland: The Swiss are skillful with their hands. The machinery and tools they make are noted for their fineness., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 74-verso (Box 1607)
  - Tunnels of the Axenstrasse, Overhanging Lake Lucerne, Switzerland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 75 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Tunnels of the Axenstrasse, Lake Lucerne, Switzerland: In almost the exact center of Switzerland lies Lake Lucrene, perhaps the most, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 75-verso (Box 1607)
  - Maria-Theresein Strasse and Pillar of St. Anne, Innsbruck, Austria., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 76 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: The Street of Maria Theresa, Innsbruck, Austria: Innsbruck, one of the most beautifully situated cities of Europe, with a population in, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 76-verso (Box 1607)
  - A Valley Deep in the Tyrolian Alps, Austria., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 77 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: A Valley Deep in the Tyrolean Alps, Austria: The treaty of St. Germain established Austria as a republic of 34,000 square miles, an area, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 77-verso (Box 1607)
  - "Wendlandhof," Old Country Inn, Tyrol, Austria., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 78 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: An Old Country Inn among the Austrian Alps, Austria: Towering high above green alpine meadows are two parallel ranges which flank, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 78-verso (Box 1607)
  - Picturesque Church in the Mountains, near Semmering, Austria., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 79 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Picturesque Church in the Mountains, near Semmering, Austria: The eastern limits of the Alps are marked in Austria by the Semmering, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 79-verso (Box 1607)
  - The Franzens-Ring, Vienna-Regarded by Many as Architecturally "the Finest Street in Europe.", circa late 1920s - 1930s; 80 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: The Franzens-Ring, Vienna, the Finest Street in Europe: Vienna, the capital of the Austrian Republic and before the World War capital of, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 80-verso (Box 1607)
  - Hungarian Shepherd and His Flock on the Hortobagy Plain, Hungary., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 81 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Hungarian Shepherd and His Flock on the Hortobagy Plain, Hungary: The Hortobagy or Alfold Plain in the northeast part of Hungary has, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 81-verso (Box 1607)
  - The Superb Palace of Buda from the Szechonyi Bridge across the Danube, Budapest, Hungary., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 82 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Palace of Buda, from the Szechonyi Bridge, Budapest, Hungary: The traveller who visits Budapest will be surprised and delighted with, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 82-verso (Box 1607)
  - Primitive Methods of Transportation Still Prevailing in Rural Hungary., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 83 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Primitive Transportation on the Great Plains of Hungary: Until the close of the World War, Hungary was a kingdom which, united with, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 83-verso (Box 1607)
  - Country Girls Hoeing Potatoes, Hungary., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 84 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Country Girls Hoeing Potatoes, Hungary: Through treaties following defeat in the World War, where self-determination of nations brought, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 84-verso (Box 1607)
  - Historic Carlstein Castle, Medieval Stronghold of Bohemian Kings, near Praha (Prague), circa late 1920s - 1930s; 85 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Carlstein Castle, Medieval Stronghold, near Prague: Bohemia is a province of Czechoslovakia, the new country which resulted from, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 85-verso (Box 1607)
  - Praha (Prague), the Capital of Czechoslovakia Looking to the Ancient Royal Palace and St. Vitus Cathedral., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 86 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Prague, the capital of Czechoslovakia: Prague is the capital of one of the most important of the various new countries which emerged, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 86-verso (Box 1607)
  - Old Bridge and Winding Canal on Left Bank of Moldau River, Praha (Prague), Czechoslovakia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 87 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: An Old Bridge and Winding Canal, Praha, Czechoslovakia: A map of Czechoslovakia show a renaming since the war of many cities and, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 87-verso (Box 1607)
  - Characteristic Village Scene, Trilinak, Czechoslovakia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 88 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Characteristic Village Scene, Trilinak, Czechoslovakia: Slovakia, one of the four states of Czechslovakia, is to Prague and Bohemia what, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 88-verso (Box 1607)
  - Polish School Children, the Village of Zakopane, Galicia, Poland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 89 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Polish School Children in Village of Zakopane, Galicia: One of the most important tasks confronting the newly formed Republic of Poland, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 89-verso (Box 1607)
  - Palace of the Ancient Polish Kings, Cracow, Galicia, Poland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 90 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Palace of the Ancient Polish Kings, Cracow, Galicia, Poland: It is safe to say that no other city in Poland possesses so many historic buildings, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 90-verso (Box 1607)
  - A Busy Morning in the Market Place, Viborg, Finland., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 91 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: A Busy Morning in Market Place, Viborg, Finland: Viborg is the capital of the province of the same name, near the head of the Bay of Viborg on, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 91-verso (Box 1607)
  - Avenue of Fountains at Peterhof, Former Summer Palace of the Czars of Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 92 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Avenue of Fountains at Peterhof, Former Summer Palace of Czars: Peterhof was built in 1720 as a summer residence by Peter the Great and..., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 92-verso (Box 1607)
  - Interesting Peasant Types in the Street of a Rural Village in Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 93 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Peasant Types in Rura Village, Russia: In a country so vast as Russia, and where conditions are in such a radical state of change, it is impossible, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 93-verso (Box 1607)
  - The Kremlin in Winter, Seen from the Moskva River, Moscow, Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 94 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: The Kremlin from the Moskva, River, Russia: We are looking from the Moskva River to the central part of the Kremlin, crowded with, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 94-verso (Box 1607)
  - Russian Peasant Tilling a Fertile Field with a Primitive Native Plow., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 95 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Russian Farmer Tilling Field with Primitive Native Plow: Whatever radical innovations the new political leaders of Russia have introduced, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 95-verso (Box 1607)
  - Cloth Market in the Great Fair of Nijni-Novgorod, Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 96 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Cloth Market in the Great Fair of Nijni-Novgorod, Russia: The city of Nijni-Novgorod, at the head of navigation of the mighty Volga River, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 96-verso (Box 1607)
  - Magnificent Heights of Mount Kasbek (16,545 ft.), Caucasus Mountains, Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 97 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Magnificent Heights of Mount Kasbek (16,545 ft.), Caucasus Mountains, Russia: The Caucasus range extends from the Strait of Kerch, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 97-verso (Box 1607)
  - Russian Fishermen drawing their Nets on the Lower Volga River, Russia., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 98 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: The Grinding Toil of the Volga Fishermen, Russia: Whether in the old days of the supremacy of the czars or at the present under the equally, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 98-verso (Box 1607)
  - Exporting Wheat at Odessa on the Black Sea, the Ukraine., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 99 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Exporting Wheat at Odessa on the Black Sea, the Ukraine: Odessa was for a long time the most important port of all Russia, because its, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 99-verso (Box 1607)
  - The Handsome Opera House of Odessa, the Ukraine., circa late 1920s - 1930s; 100 (Box 1607)
  - Verso: Opera House of Odessa, Ukraine: It is hard to realize that this greatest port of Russia on the Black Sea, familiar to the world for many, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 100-verso (Box 1607)
  Box 1608
- Stereographic Cards, 2.1.8
  - Venerable tombs and Italian rural life beside the Appian Way, Rome, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 1 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Venerable tombs and Italian rural life beside the Appian Way, Rome, Italy: Twenty-two hundred years have passed since the Roman censor Appius Caludius began construction, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 1-verso (Box 1608)
  - The ruins of the Colosseum, Rome, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 2 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The ruins of the Colosseum, Rome, Italy: For centuries Rome was the mistress of the world, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 2-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Cathedral in the "Flower of All Cities," Florence, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 3 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Cathedral in the "Flower of All Cities," Florence, Italy: The Florentine Republic, near the end of the thirteenth century, made a proclamation, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 3-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Campanile, Doges' Palace and the Prison, Venice, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 4 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Campanile, Doges' Palace and the Prison, Venice, Italy: We are on a broad lagoon, or opening of the Adriatic Sea, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 4-verso (Box 1608)
  - An oriental poem in marble, mosaic and gold - Saint Mark's Cathedral - Venice, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 5 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: An oriental poem in marble, mosaic and gold - Saint Mark's Cathedral - Venice, Italy: This beautiful religious edifice was begun eleven centuries ago, in 830, as a shrine, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 5-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Rialto and the Grand Canal, Venice, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 6 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Rialto and the Grand Canal, Venice, Italy: We are in the northern part of the city, looking across the largest of its hundred and forty-seven canals, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 6-verso (Box 1608)
  - Lake Como and the surrounding mountians, from the Landing, Como, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 7 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Lake Como and the surrounding mountians, from the Landing, Como, Italy: Lake Como, the Lacus Larius of the Romans, is one of the most celebrated of the lakes in Lombardy, northern Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 7-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Campo Santo, famous palace of the dead, Genoa, Italy, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 8 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Campo Santo, famous palace of the dead, Genoa, Italy: We are about one and a hlaf miles beyond the city limits in the beautifully located cemetery beside the River Bisagno, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 8-verso (Box 1608)
  - General view of the Ancient Stronghold of Corsican Warriors, Corte, Island of Corsica, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 9 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: General view of the Ancient Stronghold of Corsican Warriors, Corte, Island of Corsica, France: Corsica is a large island in the Mediterranean, forming a department of France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 9-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Cathedral and harbor, Marseilles, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 10 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Cathedral and harbor, Marseilles, France: It is the romance of the sea and the galamour of ships that makes Marseilles so fascinating, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 10-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Casino at Monte Carlo, the world's famous gambling resort, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 11 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Casino at Monte Carlo, the world's famous gambling resort: This famous Mediterranean gambling resort is situated in southwestern Francfe in the principality of Monaco, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 11-verso (Box 1608)
  - Among the spacious and luxuriant gardens of Mentone, in Southern France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 12 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Among the spacious and luxuriant gardens of Mentone, in Southern France: these gardens are laid out after the Italian fashion in strict conformity to line and arc, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 12-verso (Box 1608)
  - Where France and Switzerland meet - from the trail to the Brevent Village of Chamonix, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 13 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Where France and Switzerland meet - from the trail to the Brevent Village of Chamonix, France: None who have been privileged to visit this little village, looking in the distance like a collection of carboard houses, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 13-verso (Box 1608)
  - Looking E. from St. Quentin to the battlefields of 1870, over Metz, Moselle, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 14 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Looking E. from St. Quentin to the battlefields of 1870, over Metz, Moselle, France: We are on a hill at the west side of the city of Metz, which Caeser described as one of the oldest and most important towns, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 14-verso (Box 1608)
  - Restored cathedral of Reims with equestrian statue of Joan of Arc before It, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 15 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Restored cathedral of Reims with equestrian statue of Joan of Arc before It, France: Before us, mervelous in its grace of outline and richness of decoration, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 15-verso (Box 1608)
  - Vineyards covering sunny fields at Ay near Eperuay, Champagne District, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 16 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Vineyards covering snny fields at Ay near Eperuay, Champagne District, France: This is a characteristic scene in the champagne district of Francfe where thousands upon thousands of acres, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 16-verso (Box 1608)
  - Gorgeous reception room of Catherine de Medici in the Royal Palace of Fontainebleau, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 17 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Gorgeous reception room of Catherine de Medici in the Royal Palace of Fontainebleau, France: The Palace of Fontainebleau typifies admirably two of the outstanding characteristics of the French people, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 17-verso (Box 1608)
  - Champs Elysees from the Arch of Triumph to the Place de la Concorde, Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 18 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Champs Elysees from the Arch of Triumph to the Place de la Concorde, Paris, France: This lofty station on the summit of Napoleon's triumphal arch gives a marvelously fine out look over the city, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 18-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Arch of Triumph, Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 19 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Arch of Triumph, Paris, France: Paris is often referred to as the most beautiful city in the world, and it well deserves that description, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 19-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Eiffel Tower and Champs de Mars from the Trocadero Palace, Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 20 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Eiffel Tower and Champs de Mars from the Trocadero Palace, Paris, France: No Frenchman and no visitor to France of the present day could imagine a perspective of Paris, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 20-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Fountain of the Mediel in the beautiful Renaissance Gardens of the Luxembourg, Paris, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 21 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Fountain of the Mediel in the beautiful Renaissance Gardens of the Luxembourg, Paris: "The prettiest and pleasantest spot in Paris," writes the very competent observer, Augustus Hare, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 21-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Old City Island and the Seine, S.E. from the Lovure, Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 22 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Old City Island and the Seine, S.E. from the Lovure, Paris, France: This beautiful city is Paris, the capital of France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 22-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Glorious Cathedral of Notre Dame Dominates Island which was the cradle of Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 23 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Glorious Cathedral of Notre Dame Dominates Island which was the cradle of Paris, France: Away back in the year 375 early converts to Christianity built a church here on the island which is now the heart of Paris, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 23-verso (Box 1608)
  - The world's most splendid temple of music - the opera at Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 24 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The world's most splendid temple of music - the opera at Paris, France: The Opera, more accurately entitle the National Academy of Music, was founded in 1671 and is liberally subsidized by the governemtn, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 24-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Classic Madeleine. One of the most famous and frequented churches in Paris, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 25 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Classic Madeleine. One of the most famous and frequented churches in Paris, France: This famous church, a perfect replica of early Greek architecture, is situated on one of the liveliest corners of Paris, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 25-verso (Box 1608)
  - The American Military Cemetery, at Suresnes, overlooking the city of Paris, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 26 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The American Military Cemetery, at Suresnes, overlooking the city of Paris: On the eastern slope of the noble height of Mont St. Valerian lies this beautiful spot, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 26-verso (Box 1608)
  - Autumn in Brittany, peasants threshing grain on a farm near Carhaix, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 27 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Autumn in Brittany, peasants threshing grain on a farm near Carhaix, France: This is one of the few sections of this part of northwestern France where soil and climate, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 27-verso (Box 1608)
  - Breton peasants making wooden shoes in the forest near Clohars-Carnoet, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 28 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Breton peasants making wooden shoes in the forest near Clohars-Carnoet, France: The men and women at work in this pleasant forest clearing are inhabitants of the ancient Province of Brittany, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 28-verso (Box 1608)
  - Gossip beside the Oust River, whose waters reflect the Castle Josselin, France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 29 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Gossip beside the Oust River, whose waters reflect the Castle Josselin, France: We are gazing upon one of the charming bits of scenery which so delight the tourist in France, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 29-verso (Box 1608)
  - Picturesque beauty of an old farmhouse near Lemona, Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 30 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Picturesque beauty of an old farmhouse near Lemona, Spain: This is in the fruitful wine producing valley of the Nervion river, in Northern Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 30-verso (Box 1608)
  - Monastery of Montserrat where tradition locates Castle of Knights of the Holy Grail - near Barcelona, Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 31 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Monastery of Montserrat where tradition locates Castle of Knights of the Holy Grail - near Barcelona, Spain: This point is most easily reached from Barcelona, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 31-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Alhambra, for centuries the seat of Moorish power - looking toward the Snowy Sierras, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 32 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Alhambra, for centuries the seat of Moorish power - looking toward the Snowy Sierras: When the Moors of Northern Africa had annexed sufficient territory on their native continent, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 32-verso (Box 1608)
  - Court of the Lions, Alhambra Palace, Granada, Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 33 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Court of the Lions, Alhambra Palace, Granada, Spain: For nearly eight hundred years the Moors held sway in Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 33-verso (Box 1608)
  - Imposing gorge of the Guadalevin and the New Bridge,Ronda, Spain, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 34 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Imposing gorge of the Guadalevin and the New Bridge,Ronda, Spain: On a rock not unlike that of Gibraltar and about 40 miles north of the latter, the town of Ronda rises from a sea of truck gardens, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 34-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Rock of Gibraltar, an important stronghold of the British Empire, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 35 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Rock of Gibraltar, an important stronghold of the British Empire: This is one of the important strongholds of the British Empire, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 35-verso (Box 1608)
  - Cloisters of Sao Jeronymo Monastery, now orphanage, looking across court, near Belem, Lisbon, Portugal, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 36 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Cloisters of Sao Jeronymo Monastery, now orphanage, looking across court, near Belem, Lisbon, Portugal: Out here in a western suburb of Lisbon, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 36-verso (Box 1608)
  - Beautiful ballroom in the Stock Exchange of Oporto, city of the famous Port Wine, Portugal, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 37 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Beautiful ballroom in the Stock Exchange of Oporto, city of the famous Port Wine, Portugal: In harmony of color, elegance of design and perfection of detail this beautiful ballroom perhaps has no superior, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 37-verso (Box 1608)
  - Ox team and sledge, the only kind of carriage used in Funchal, Madeira Islands, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 38 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Ox team and sledge, the only kind of carriage used in Funchal, Madeira Islands: As our ship approaches the Madeira Islands, on the Atlantic Ocean, 550 miles southwest of Lisbon, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 38-verso (Box 1608)
  - Former stronghold of Barbary Pirates, ocean front approach and mosque in distance, Algiers, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 39 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Former stronghold of Barbary Pirates, ocean front approach and mosque in distance, Algiers: Algiers, the capital of Algeria, is situated on the western slope of the Bay of Algiers, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 39-verso (Box 1608)
  - Mediterranean Luxuriance - Palm Avenue in the Jardin d'Essai, Algiers, Algeria, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 40 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: Mediterranean Luxuriance - Palm Avenue in the Jardin d'Essai, Algiers, Algeria: The large and beautiful Jardin d'Essai in a suburb to the south of the city is a rich example of the luxuriant vegetation, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 40-verso (Box 1608)
  - An Arab woman in street costume, Algiers, Algeria, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 41 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: An Arab woman in street costume, Algiers, Algeria: Algiers, ofren called the "white city," is an important French port of Northern Africa, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 41-verso (Box 1608)
  - A mingling of Orient and Occident - the Muski, liveliest of the real streets of Cairo, Egypt, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 42 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: A mingling of Orient and Occident - the Muski, liveliest of the real streets of Cairo, Egypt: Cairo, the "diamond stud in the handle of the fan of the Delta," as it has often been styled, is 136 miles southward from Alexandria, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 42-verso (Box 1608)
  - The Suez Canal from an ocean liner, looking North, Egypt, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 43 (Box 1608)
  - Verso: The Suez Canal from an ocean liner, looking North, Egypt: What two seas does the Suez Canal connect? Next to the Panama Canal, the Suez Canal is the one most heard of, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 43-verso (Box 1608)
  - Road to the pyramids - westward toward Gizeh from a point near Cairo, Egypt, circa late 1920s - 1930s; 44 (Box 1608)